madwhips.com 2014-12-17

# MadWhips

Details
     Published: 26 February 2014 
     Hits: 24284 

Thank you for using MadWhips! We wrote this policy to help you understand what information we collect, how we use it, and what choices you have. Because our services are provided online, some of the concepts below are a little technical, but we’ve tried our best to explain things in a simple and clear way. We welcome your questions and comments on this policy. Capitalized terms used but not defined herein have the meanings assigned to them in the Terms of Service Agreement (“ **Agreement** ”).

While we have always respected our users privacy and safeguarded their personal information, we have strengthened our commitment to protecting personal information as a result of Canada’s Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA).  PIPEDA, which came into effect on April, 2000, sets out the ground rules for how Ontario businesses may collect, use and disclose personal information.

We will inform our users of why and how we collect, use and disclose their information, obtain their consent where required, and only handle their information in a manner that a reasonable person would consider appropriate in the circumstances.

**What information do we collect?**

We collect information in two ways:

1\. When you give it to us or give us permission to obtain it.

When you sign up for or use our products and services, you voluntarily give us certain information. This can include your name, profile photo, comments, likes, email address you used to sign up, and any other information you provide us. If you’re using MadWhips on your mobile device, you can also choose to provide us with location data.

You also may give us permission to access your information in other services. For example, you may link your Facebook account to MadWhips, which allows us to obtain information from those accounts (e.g., your friends or contacts). The information we obtain from those services often depends on your settings or their privacy policies, so be sure to check what those are.

2\. We also get technical information when you use our products or services or apps that have MadWhips features.

These days, whenever you use a website, mobile application, or other Internet service, there’s certain information that almost always gets created and recorded automatically. The same is true when you use our products. Here are some of the types of information we collect:

Log Data. 

When you use MadWhips or go to a webpage or use an app that has MadWhips features (like our “Add To Collections” button), our servers automatically record information (“ **log data** ”) including information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website or your mobile app sends when you’re using it. This log data may include your Internet Protocol address, the address of the web pages you visited that had MadWhips features, browser type and settings, the date and time of your request, how you used MadWhips, and cookie data.

Cookie data.   
Depending on how you’re accessing our products and services, we may use “cookies” (a small text file sent by your computer each time you visit our website, unique to your MadWhips account or your browser), or similar technologies to record log data. When we use cookies, we may use “session” cookies (that last until you close your browser) or “persistent” cookies (that last until you or your browser delete them). For example, we may use cookies to store your language preferences or other MadWhips settings so you don‘t have to set them up every time you visit MadWhips. Some of the cookies we use are associated with your MadWhips account (including personal information about you, such as the email address you gave us), and other cookies are not.

Device Information. In addition to log data, we may also collect information about the device you’re using MadWhips on, including what type of device it is, what operating system you’re using, device settings, unique device identifiers, and crash data. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings. For example, different types of information are available depending on whether you’re using a Mac or a PC, or an iPhone or an Android phone. To learn more about what information your device makes available to us, please also check the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider.

**How do we use the information we collect?**

We use the information we collect to provide our products and services to you and make them better, develop new products, and protect MadWhips and our users. 

We also use the information we collect to offer you customized content, including suggesting photos or collections you might like. 

We also use the information we collect to:

Send you updates (such as when certain activity, likes or comments, happens on MadWhips), newsletters, marketing materials and other information that may be of interest to you. For example, depending on your email notification settings, we may send you weekly updates that include links or other content you may like. You can decide to stop getting these updates by updating your account settings (or through other settings we may provide).

Help your friends and contacts find you on MadWhips. For example, if you sign up using a Facebook account, we may help your Facebook friends find your account on MadWhips when they first sign up for MadWhips. Or, we may allow people to search for your account on MadWhips using your email address.

The information we collect may be “personally identifiable” (meaning it can be used to specifically identify you as a unique person) or “non-personally identifiable” (meaning it can’t be used to specifically identify you). We use both types of information, and combinations of both types, as described above. We may use or store information wherever MadWhips does business, including countries outside your own.

**What choices do you have about your information?**

Our goal is to give you simple and meaningful choices over your information. If you have a MadWhips account, many of the choices you have on MadWhips are built directly in to our products, services or your account settings. 

For example, you can:

Access and change information in your profile page at any time. 

Link or unlink your MadWhips account from an account on another service (e.g., Facebook). For some services (like Facebook), you can also choose whether or not to publish your activity on MadWhips to that service.

Close your account at any time. When you close your account, we’ll deactivate it and remove your photos and collections from MadWhips. We may retain archived copies of your information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes (including to help address fraud and spam).

You may have choices available to you through the device or software you use to access MadWhips. 

For example:

The browser you use may provide you with the ability to control cookies or other types of local data storage.

Your mobile device may provide you with choices around how and whether location or other data is shared with us.

To learn more about these choices, please see the information provided by the device or software provider.

**How do we share the information we collect?**

MadWhips is a tool people use to upload, share & collection automotive photography of their favorite cars.  When you upload photographs or post comments, anyone can view them. You may also provide us with profile page information that that anyone can view. The other limited instances where we may share your personal information include:

When we have your consent. This includes sharing information with other services (like Facebook) when you’ve chosen to link to your MadWhips account to those services or publish your activity on MadWhips to them. For example, you can choose to publish your photos or collections to Facebook or Twitter.

We may employ third party companies or individuals to process personal information on our behalf based on our instructions and in compliance with this

 Privacy Policy. For example, we may share data with a security consultant to help us get better at identifying spam or with our accountants to make sure we’re keeping the books right. In addition, some of the information we request may be collected by third party providers on our behalf. For more information about the providers we use, please see our Help Center.

If we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety, rights, or property of the public, any person, or MadWhips; or to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.

We may engage in a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, reorganization, or similar transaction or proceeding that involves the transfer of the information described in this Privacy Policy.

We may also share aggregated or non-personally identifiable information with our partners or others. For example, we may tell a business using MadWhips how many people re-added something they shared, or the percentage of people who click on a photo after viewing it.

**Our Policy on Children’s Information**

**How do we make changes to this policy?**

We may change this policy from time to time, and if we do we’ll post any changes on this page. If you continue to use MadWhips after those changes are in effect, you agree to the revised policy. If the changes are significant, we may provide more prominent notice or obtain your consent as required by law.

**The Role of our Privacy Officer**

Our  Privacy Officer is responsible for ensuring MadWhips’ compliance with this Privacy Policy and the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act. 

You should direct any complaints, concerns or questions regarding MadWhips’ compliance in writing to our Privacy Officer. If our Privacy Officer is unable to resolve your concerns, you may also write to the Ontario Privacy Commissioner.   
The contact information our Privacy Officer is:  [privacy@madwhips.com](mailto:privacy@madwhips.com)
